# Leo Kalshteyn

646-262-9470 | leo.kalshteyn@gmail.com | GitHub: gorgutzz | LinkedIn: leokalshtevn | Portfolio: leokalshtevn.com

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and various frontend based programming languages utilizing a background in IT hardware systems. Broadly knowledgeable in the latest web technologies as well as streamlined principles and techniques in app development. Possess strong skills in conveying technical information and learning new concepts.

## **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

**Planet Database** - A javascript app that allows users to add exoplanets to known star systems in the galaxy.

GitHub | Demo

- Utilized PostgreSQL to store stars and planets on Rails backend.
- Leveraged RESTful APIs to display planetary/star systems to the frontend via the backend app.
- Enabled Rack CORS middleware for handling cross domain AJAX calls.

**Museum Manager** - A rails app that allows users to take the role of a curator where they can manage museum exhibits.

GitHub | Demo

- Leveraged OmniAuth to authenticate users via GitHub for sign up process.
- Implemented bcrypt to hash passwords for additional security.
- Incorporates the Bootstrap framework to create a responsive experience on the frontend.

**Book Collection** - A Sinatra app that allows users to register and create a library of their favorite books for reference.

GitHub | Demo

- Created a custom user controller that allows user signup, login, and logout functionality by validating sessions.
- Integrated the Rackflash gem for header flash notifications on submission and login actions.
- Debugged various code issues using Pry during development phase of backend.

**Quiz Buzz** - A React app which prompts the user with true of false questions based on Computer Science.

GitHub | Demo

- Utilized React to create a single page application.
- Written in TypeScript to implement cleaner and more efficient testable code.

## **SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, Python, JavaScript, ¡Query, React, Redux, Node.js, HTML, CSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Webpack, Heroku, Git, Unix, Blockchain

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## Counting Coral - New York, NY

June 2021 - Present

Web Developer, Intern

- + Collaborated on porting the Counting Coral website from Wix to the WordPress platform utilizing the Divi framework.
- + Redesigned the Counting Coral website through collaboration with the founders, translation of stakeholder vision into achievable code, and drafting new web pages in WordPress.
- + Diagnosed issues with cross browser compatibility allowing for a seamless feel across browsers.

## East Coast, LLC - New York, NY

April 2016 - June 2020

Technician

+ Installed, configured, and provided on-site support for wired/wireless surveillance equipment, including Network Video Recorders (NVR), IP Cameras (IPC), Wi-Fi access points (AP) and associated network cabling.

#### Opus Energy, LLC - New York, NY

September 2014 - February 2016

Technician

- + Installed, serviced and troubleshooted HVAC equipment including control modules, actuators, temperature/pressure sensors and other measuring devices, circulating pumps, and various fans.
- + Control, adjustment and operational checks of components to assure reliability of HVAC equipment.

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School - New York, NY

February 2020

+ Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript online program.

## Hunter College - New York, NY

March 2017

+ Computer Science